Register of the David Walter collection
Hoover Institution Archives
David Walter collection
1964-1987
92002
Hoover Institution Archives
26 manuscript boxes (10.4 linear feet)
Serial issues, pamphlets, leaflets, newsletters, bulletins, and election campaign material relating to libertarianism, issued by the Libertarian Party and other libertarian organizations in the United States, including many state, local, and campus libertarian groups, and by libertarian organizations in Canada.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1992.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection consists of serial issues, bulletins, pamphlets, newsletters, campaign material, and newspapers circulated and created by the Libertarian Party of the United States, the Libertarian Party of Canada, and various other libertarian organizations, including those headquartered in states and in local communities, and student run groups on various college campuses. These materials were collected by David Walter, an editor of several publications and active member of the Libertarian Party and Society for Individual Liberty.
Libertarian Party.; Walter, David, collector.; Laissez-faire.; Libertarianism--Canada.; Libertarianism--United States.; Student movements--United States.
- Biographical File, circa 1970 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Posters, stickers, photographs, and other material relating to David Walter and his activities in the Libertarian Party.
- Correspondence File, 1970-1986 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Printed Matter, 1964-1987
  - State Publications, 1978-1987
    Publications created specifically by state libertarian parties in the United States. Includes serial issues and information on national conventions.
    - Alaska, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - Arizona, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - California, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 1: 5-6)
    - Colorado, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 1: 7, Box-folder 2: 1)
    - Connecticut, 1981-1987 (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - Delaware, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 2: 3-4)
    - Florida, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - Georgia, 1979-1987 (Box-folder 2: 6-7)
    - Hawaii, 1979 (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - Idaho, 1979 (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - Illinois, 1978-1987 (Box-folder 2: 10-11, Box-folder 3: 1)
    - Indiana, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - Iowa, 1979 (Box-folder 3: 3)
    - Kentucky, circa 1985 (Box-folder 3: 4)
    - Maryland, 1979-1987 (Box-folder 3: 5)
    - Massachussetts, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 3: 6)
    - Michigan, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 3: 7)
    - Minnesota, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 3: 8-9)
    - Montana, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - Nevada, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 3: 11)
    - New Jersey, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 3: 12-13)
    - New York, 1979-1985 (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - North Carolina, 1979-1987 (Box-folder 4: 2)
    - Oklahoma, 1981 (Box-folder 4: 3)
    - Oregon, 1984 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - Tennessee, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 4: 5)
    - Texas, circa 1978 (Box-folder 4: 6-7)
    - Utah, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 4: 8)
    - Vermont, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 4: 9)
    - Virginia, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 4: 10)
    - Washington, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 5: 1-2)
    - Washington DC, circa 1979 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - Wisconsin, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 5: 4-5)
    - Wyoming, 1981 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - National Publications, 1964-1987
    Serial issues of nationally and internationally distributed libertarian publications.
    - The 4th Estate, circa 1969 (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - A Is A, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 5: 8-9)
    - The Abolitionist, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 5: 10-12)
    - The Activist Letter The Activist Letter, circa 1982 (Box-folder 5: 13)
    - Against the Wall, undated (Box-folder 5: 14)
    - The Agorist Institute, 1986 (Box-folder 5: 15)
    - American Defense, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 5: 16)
    - American Opium, 1969 (Box-folder 5: 17)
    - Association for Rational Environmental Alternatives Bulletin, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 5: 18)
    - The Arena, 1969 (Box-folder 5: 19)
    - The Ark, undated (Box-folder 5: 20)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers, undated (Box-folder 5: 21)
    - Association of Libertarian Feminists, 1978-1985 (Box-folder 5: 22-23)
    - The Atlantis News, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 5: 24)
    - Aware, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 5: 25)
    - Babson Liberated Press, 1969 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Bulletin, 1984 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Bullsheet, 1969 (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - Campus Courier, 1969 (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - Citizens Asserting Supremacy Over Taxation, 1981 (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - Catalyst, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - Chronicle, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 6: 7)
    - Claustrophobia, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 6: 8-9)
    - College Journal, 1969 (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - The College Paper, 1970 (Box-folder 6: 11)
    - Commentary, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - Communique, 1970 (Box-folder 6: 13)
    - The Continental Line, 1978 (Box-folder 6: 14)
    - The Continental Safari, 1970 (Box-folder 6: 15)
    - Counterpoint, 1970 (Box-folder 6: 16)
    - The Dandelion, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - A Different Drummer, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - The Diode, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 3)
    - Do-It, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - Dollars and Sense, 1971-1981 (Box-folder 7: 5-6)
    - Efficacy, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 7: 7-8)
    - Enviromental Alternatives, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - Ergo, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 8: 1-4)
    - Factotum, 1968 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - The Familist, 1983 (Box-folder 9: 2)
    - The Fire Bringer, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - First Person-Singular, 1975 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - Focus, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 9: 5-6)
    - Free Life, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 9: 7)
    - Free Market Reporter, 1977 (Box-folder 9: 8-9)
    - Free Press Network, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 9: 10)
    - Free Ranger, 1970 (Box-folder 9: 11)
    - Free Star, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 9: 12)
    - Free Trade, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 9: 13)
    - Free World, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 9: 14)
    - Free World Chronicle, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 9: 15)
    - Freedom, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 9: 16)
    - Freedom Network News, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 9: 17)
    - Freedom: The Only Consistent Choice, 1984 (Box-folder 9: 18)
    - Freedom Today, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - Freedom's Way, 1967 (Box-folder 10: 2)
    - Frontlines, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 10: 3-4)
    - Galatians Seven, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - The Gargoyle, 1969 (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - Hermes, 1971 (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - How to Survive a Depression, 1971 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - Independent Libertarian Commentary, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 10: 9)
    - Individual Liberty, 1974-1986 (Box-folder 10: 10)
    - Individual Liberty, 1974-1986 (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
    - Individualist, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 11: 3-4)
    - The Individualist, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 11: 5-6)
    - Influence Line, 1971 (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - Innovator, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 8)
    - Integrity, 1971 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Intellectual Activist, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - Invictus, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 12: 3-4)
    - Investment Rarities Incorporated Insights, 1981 (Box-folder 12: 5)
    - Laissez Faire Books, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - Laissez Faire Review, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - Lefevre's Journal, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - The Liberator, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 13: 4-5)
    - The Libertarian/The Libertarian Forum, 1969-1984 (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - Libertarian Alliance, undated (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Libertarian Alternative, 1975 (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - Libertarian American, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Libertarian Analysis, 1970 (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - Libertarian Church Newsletter, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Libertarian Connection, 1968-1978 (Box-folder 14: 6-7, Box-folder 15: 1-2)
    - Libertarian Conservative Thought, 1970 (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - Libertarian Digest, 1981 (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - Libertarian for Life, 1985 (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - Libertarian Party News, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 16: 1-2)
    - Libertarian Vanguard, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - Liberty Tree Catalog, 1987 (Box-folder 17: 2)
    - LibSig!, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - Life and Liberty, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - Limit!, undated (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - Living Free, 1979 (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - The Match!, 1971 (Box-folder 17: 7)
    - The Mercury, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 17: 8-9)
    - Metro Magazine, 1968 (Box-folder 17: 10)
    - Minus One, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 17: 11)
    - The New Banner, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - New Capitalist, 1971 (Box-folder 18: 2)
    - The New Individualist, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - New Libertarian Notes, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 18: 4-5)
    - New Libertarian Weekly, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - New Political Times, undated (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - The New Radical, 1968 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - New Rampart, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 19: 4)
    - Nomos, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - National Taxpayers Union Issue Perspective, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 19: 6)
    - New York Libertarians Associations, 1979 (Box-folder 19: 7)
    - On Principle, 1984 (Box-folder 19: 8)
    - The Open Sea, undated (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - Option, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 19: 10, Box-folder 20: 1)
    - Outlook, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - Pillar, 1970 (Box-folder 20: 3)
    - The Por Populi, 1969 (Box-folder 20: 4)
    - Porcupine Philosophy, 1979 (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - The Pragmatist, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - PreInform, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 20: 7-8)
    - Persuasion, 1964 (Box-folder 20: 9)
    - Prometheus, 1971 (Box-folder 20: 10)
    - Protos, 1970 (Box-folder 20: 11-12)
    - Rap, 1970 (Box-folder 20: 13)
    - The Rational Individualist, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 20: 14-16)
    - Renaissance, 1975 (Box-folder 20: 17)
    - The Republic of Minerva Project, 1973 (Box-folder 20: 18)
    - Rights by Right, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 20: 19)
    - Rip-off Resistance, 1973 (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - Ripon Forum, 1973 (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - Robert White's Duck Book, 1980 (Box-folder 21: 3)
    - The Shadow, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - SidBits, 1981 (Box-folder 21: 5)
    - Sign of the Dollar, undated (Box-folder 21: 6)
    - Society for Individual Liberty White Paper, undated (Box-folder 21: 7)
    - Simon Jester, 1977 (Box-folder 21: 8)
    - The Skeptic, 1971 (Box-folder 21: 9)
    - Students for a Libertarian Society Action, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 21: 10)
    - Students for a Libertarian Society Liberty, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 21: 11-12)
    - Smart Set, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 21: 13)
    - Society for Individual Liberty News, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Southern Libertarian Messenger, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 22: 2-3)
    - Southern Libertarian Review, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - The Spokesman, 1966 (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - Squat Spot, undated (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - Starboard, 1970 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Strategy, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Sunburst, 1971 (Box-folder 22: 9)
    - Tactics of the Movement of the Libertarian Left, 1984 (Box-folder 22: 10)
    - Tax Rebel News, undated (Box-folder 22: 11)
    - Thorn, 1969 (Box-folder 22: 12-13)
    - The Torch, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 22: 14, Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Tta Enterprises, undated (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - Update, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 23: 3)
    - Volition, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - The Voluntaryist, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - Western World Review, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 23: 6-7, Box-folder 24: 1)
    - World Research Ink, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 24: 2-3)
    - Young Libertarian Alliance, 1978 (Box-folder 24: 4)
- Subject File, 1968-1987
  - Cato Institute, 1979-1987 (Box-folder 24: 5)
  - Center for Independent Education, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - Center for Libertarian Studies, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 25: 2)
  - Council for a Competitive Economy, 1977-1983 (Box-folder 25: 3)
  - Ed Clark, 1980 (Box-folder 25: 4)
  - The Independent Institute, undated (Box-folder 25: 5)
  - Institute for Contemporary Studies, 1981 (Box-folder 25: 6)
  - Infra, 1969 (Box-folder 25: 7)
  - Institute for Humane Studies, 1981 (Box-folder 25: 8)
  - International Libertarians, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 25: 9)
  - Jack Schroeder & Associates/Federal Trade Commission, 1981 (Box-folder 25: 10)
  - Judith Jones, undated (Box-folder 25: 11)
  - Libertarian Alliance, undated (Box-folder 25: 12)
  - Libertarian Deseret Society, 1981 (Box-folder 25: 13)
  - Libertarian Lawyers, 1978 (Box-folder 25: 14)
  - Libertarian Lawyers Council, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 25: 15)
  - Libertarian Party Canada, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 25: 16)
  - Libertarian Press Association, undated (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Libertarianism, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 26: 2)
  - National Taxpayers Union, 1981 (Box-folder 26: 3)
  - Pacific Institute, 1981 (Box-folder 26: 4)
  - Rampart Institute, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 26: 5)
  - Reason Foundation, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 26: 6)
  - Seattle Libertarians, 1977 (Box-folder 26: 7)
  - Society for Individual Liberty, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 26: 8)
  - Society for Libertarian Life, 1978 (Box-folder 26: 9)
  - Students for a Libertarian Society, 1981 (Box-folder 26: 10)
  - Unparty, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 26: 11)
  - Walter Williams, undated (Box-folder 26: 12)
  - Young Americans for Freedom, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 13)